<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MARCUS TANNENBERG</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MARCUS TANNENBERG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Marcus Tannenberg</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Development aid from dictators: Damaging for democracy?</title>
      <link>/posts/aut-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/aut-aid/</guid>
      <description>I joined Staffan Lindberg to edit an issue of APSA’s Annals of Comparative Democratization focused on development aid from autocratic donors. With contributions from Sarah Blodgett Bermeo, Christine Hackenesh, Julia Bader, Brad Parks and Austin Strange we put together what I think is a great issue taking stock of what we know about autocratic aid and democratization. Read it here. You can also find my own contribution below.
My Issue Editor’s Note How are the prospects for democracy in the developing world shaped by the rising amounts of aid from donor countries led by dictators?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Censorship in Authoritarian States: Response bias in measures of popular support in China</title>
      <link>/posts/china-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/china-lists/</guid>
      <description>Together with Darrel Robinson we ran four list experiments in mainland China in 2017 in order to evaluate self-censorship on items commonly used in comparative politics to measure regime support. In short there is quite a lot of self-censorship going on, which help explain the comparatively high levels of reported regime support in China. The paper is published in Research &amp;amp; Politics and is open access.
Abstract The study of popular support for authoritarian regimes has long relied on the assumption that respondents provide truthful answers to surveys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Scraping Swedish Regents</title>
      <link>/posts/web-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/web-scraping/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by this gist from Alex Coppock which scrape and create a graph displaying the age and years of tenure of US presidents, I set out to do something similar for Swedish Regents. I had not seen a graph like this and think its a rather cool way of displaying data. Let’s call this an age-tenure graph. In addition to creating the graph it was a good opportunity to practice some simple web scarping, and using the rvest package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyrical masterminds&#39; popularity on Spotify</title>
      <link>/posts/rappers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/rappers/</guid>
      <description>After seeing Matthew Daniels fantastic data viz on The Largest Vocabulary In Hip Hop, in which he calculates and compares the unique number of words in rappers’ first 35,000 lyrics I wanted to know how the lyrical masterminds compared in popularity. From eyeballing the data there seem to be a positive correlation between vocab size and my preference: Wutang, A Tribe Called Quest, De La Soul, Beastie Boys all have well above average estimated vocabularies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regimes of the World (RoW)</title>
      <link>/posts/row/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/row/</guid>
      <description>Together with Anna Lührmann and Staffan I. Lindberg, we leverage V-Dem’s excellent data to code any given country and year as either a Liberal Democracy , Electoral Democracy , Electoral Autocracy , or Closed Autocracies . The categorization is based on V-Dem indicators that are updated annually, and the The article describing our coding schema, and comparing RoW to extant data sets is freely available from open access journal Politics and Governance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Autocratic Trust Bias</title>
      <link>/posts/autocratic-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/autocratic-trust/</guid>
      <description>PDF
Abstract Because of a perceived risk of repressive action, some survey questions are likely sensitive in more autocratic countries while less so in more democratic countries. Yet survey data on potentially sensitive topics are frequently used in comparative research despite concerns about comparability. In a novel approach to examining the comparability of politically sensitive questions, I employ a multilevel analysis with more than 140,000 respondents in 36 African countries to test for systematic bias when survey respondents believe (fear) that the government, rather than an independent research institute, has commissioned the survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Development Work</title>
      <link>/posts/eba.report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/eba.report/</guid>
      <description>The Expert Group for Aid Studies (EBA) Report, 2015:07.
PDF; Presentation at Rosenbad
This report aims to summarize the results of research from the Quality of Government approach in terms of its importance for development and aid policy. Quality of Government (henceforth QoG) is understood as pertaining to the public institutions responsible for the implementation of public policies, i.e., the public administration and the judiciary. Qualitative as well as quantitative studies have shown that QoG factors, such as control of corruption, the rule of law, and administrative competence, have a strong positive impact on most standard measures of human well-being (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>